JOON PARK

(213) 618-9347 | <u>isp220@gmail.com</u> | 6301 Plum Way, San Diego, CA 92130

SUMMARY

Highly driven process development engineer with 8 years of experience, looking for an exciting opportunity to make a positive difference in the lives of patients via development and commercialization of new treatments and therapies, where I can contribute relevant skills and experience in biologics/gene therapy manufacturing, process development, scale-up, automation, and tech transfer to and management of CMOs.

SKILLS

- Extensive working knowledge and experience in upstream and downstream gene therapy and biologics process development bioreactor engineering and operation, media development, tech transfer, automation, scale-up, and validation activities for RRV and AAV manufacturing as well as enzyme production
- Exceptional knowledge and experience of external development and GMP manufacturing via Contract Development and Manufacturing Organizations (CDMOs), including CMO screening and selection, tech transfer, person-in-plant (PIP) support, and building of interpersonal relationships to support a successful partnership
- Expertise in mammalian and insect cell culture adherent and suspension; T-flasks, CellSTACK, shake flasks, spinner flasks, and large-scale bioreactors (up to 2500L bioreactor size)
- Excellent aseptic techniques
- Competent knowledge and experience with cell-based and other assays, such as PCR, qPCR, ELISA, Western blots, other biological/protein assays, high-tech microscopes, microplate reader, and associated software
- Well-versed in Design of Experiments (DOE), FMEA, statistical analysis, and data analysis
- Skilled in Microsoft Excel, Word, PowerPoint, MATLAB, and other relevant software
- Able to teach effectively and communicate complex concepts in terms that the audience can understand, with a genuine desire to help them
- Strong problem-solving, troubleshooting, multi-task, communication, prioritization, organizational, teamwork, and interpersonal skills; detail-oriented and a quick learner

Experience

Senior Process Engineer II, Manufacturing, Halozyme Therapeutics, San Diego, CA

May 2021 - July 2022

- Manage and assist in the transfer and performance of manufacturing techniques and processes at CMOs
- Serve as the subject matter expert (SME) on upstream biologics manufacturing process
- Provide technical input in the development of master batch records
- Perform technical review of executed batch records, technical reports, and other documents
- Collaborate closely with Quality Assurance for adherence to cGMP standards in manufacturing campaigns
- Lead investigations to address issues arising from manufacturing
- Perform upstream and downstream PIP activities to ensure successful manufacturing campaign
- Develop and deliver scientific overviews for new employees

Senior Engineer, CMC Gene Therapy Development, Neurocrine Biosciences, San Diego, CA

January 2020 - March 2021

- Worked with collaboration partners and CMOs to understand and guide the development of manufacturing process for AAV gene therapy candidates
- Served as the subject matter expert (SME) on upstream gene therapy process development
- Worked collaboratively with internal staff and collaboration partners to generate project and cost proposals, timelines, and work
 plans
- Conducted budget and invoice review for gene therapy development programs
- Developed and delivered scientific presentations at the department level (~80 people)

Process Development Engineer III, Tocagen Inc., San Diego, CA Process Development Engineer II Process Development Engineer I February 2019 – December 2019 April 2016 – February 2019 May 2014 - April 2016

Planned and conducted in-house bioreactor manufacturing runs of various types (stirred-tank, SUB, WAVE) and sizes (70-500L production size) for retroviral replicating vectors (RRVs) using suspension mammalian producer cell line

- Planned and conducted downstream filtration experiments to increase yield and optimize process for transfer to contract manufacturers
- Created and implemented schemes for automation of production run activities and write relevant codes
- Oversaw and supported technology transfer of upstream production processes to contract cGMP facilities (CMOs)
- Guided GMP production runs by providing technical expertise and person-in-plant support
- · Developed and implemented media experiments to optimize production and cell growth
- Spearheaded cell line development and scale-up projects
- Trained new team members on production processes and technical knowledge; promoted development of their careers by mentoring them and bringing them up to speed in various areas of responsibility
- Conducted cell- and PCR-based assays for product characterization

SAT/ACT Math Instructor, Elite Educational Institute, San Diego, CA

April 2015 - September 2015

• Prepared students (10th-12th graders) for their upcoming SAT or ACT exam (classroom setting as well as one-on-one tutoring) by teaching them relevant materials, helping them identify weaknesses, and reinforcing their knowledge via assignments such as homework, classwork, and quizzes

Clinical Monitoring Associate, PAREXEL International, San Diego, CA

January 2014 - May 2014

- Acted as PAREXEL's remote contact with assigned clinical sites, using judgment to assess and ensure overall integrity of study implementation and adherence to study protocol at clinical sites
- Provided clinical sites with various types of support via phone and email, including software troubleshooting, supplies, recruitment, and other study-related issues

Private Tutor, San Diego, CA

November 2011 - September 2013

- Produced successful results in various tutoring students in High School Calculus, Chemistry, and Physics
- Handled students of various skill levels, teaching them individually in ways that they can understand by identifying their strengths and weaknesses

Graduate Research, Dr. Geert Schmid-Schönbein Microcirculation Lab at UCSD, La Jolla, CA

January 2012 - June 2013

- Devised and tested an in vitro diagnostic (IVD) protocol to study the presence of peptides in urine as biomarkers for autism
- Formulated and composed a full-length scientific thesis; utilized biological assays to design a unique diagnostic technique
- Performed data analysis and risk/cost assessment; reported directly to PI regularly for progress checks

Undergraduate Research, Dr. Shu Chien Cardiovascular Lab at UCSD, La Jolla, CA

July 2009 - August 2011

- Conducted research on vascular cell mechanics to gain insight on the effects of mechanical forces within a cell
- Prepared polyacrylamide gels for the measurement and analysis of forces exerted by a cell; worked with CHO cell cultures

EDUCATION

Certification of Completion, Full Stack Web Development

University of California, San Diego Extended Studies

November 2022 La Jolla, CA

Master of Science in Bioengineering

University of California, San Diego

June 2013

Bachelor of Science in Bioengineering: Biotechnology

University of California, San Diego

La Jolla, CA June 2011

La Jolla, CA

• Jacobs School Scholar – a full scholarship for all four years, given by the School of Engineering to select top incoming freshmen in engineering majors each year

PUBLISHED WORK

- Sung Sik Hur, Juan C. del Álamo, Joon Seok Park, Yi-Shuan Li, Hong A. Nguyen, Dayu Teng, Kuei-Chun Wang, Leona Flores, Baldomero Alonso-Latorre, Juan C. Lasheras, and Shu Chien. Roles of cell confluency and fluid shear in 3 dimensional intracellular forces in endothelial cells. PNAS 2012 109 (28) 11110-11115.
- Sung Sik Hur, Yi-Shuan Li, Joon Seok Park, Ying-Li Hu, and Shu Chien. 3-dimensional forces and molecular dynamics of live cells. Proc. SPIE 7759, 77590S (2010). Aug 2010.